Macbeth is a war, drama film directed by Roman Polanski.
Scotland, 11th century.
Driven by the twisted prophecy of three witches and the ruthless ambition of his wife, warlord Macbeth, bold and brave, but also weak and hesitant,
betrays his good king and his brothers in arms and sinks into the bloody mud of a path with no return, sown with crime and suspicion.
Macbeth, played by Jon Finch.
Lady Macbeth, played by Francesca Annis.
Banquo, played by Martin Shaw.
Ross, played by John Stride.
Duncan, played by Nicholas Selby.
Macduff, played by Terence Bayler.
Macbeth (also known as The Tragedy of Macbeth or Roman Polanski's Film of Macbeth) is a 1971 historical
drama film directed by Roman Polanski, and co-written by Polanski and Kenneth Tynan.
A film adaptation of William Shakespeare's tragedy of the same name, it tells the story of
the Highland lord who becomes King of Scotland through treachery and murder.
Jon Finch and Francesca Annis star as the title character and his
wife, noted for their relative youth as actors.
Themes of historic recurrence, greater pessimism and internal ugliness in physically beautiful characters are
added to Shakespeare's story of moral decline, which is presented in a more realistic style.
Polanski opted to adapt Macbeth as a means of coping with the highly
publicized Manson Family murder of his pregnant wife, Sharon Tate.
Finding difficulty obtaining sponsorship from major studios,
Playboy Enterprises stepped in to provide funding.
Following troubled shooting around the British Isles mired by poor weather, Macbeth screened out of
competition at the 1972 Cannes Film Festival and was a commercial failure in the United States.
Initially controversial for its graphic violence and nudity, the film has since garnered generally
positive reviews, and was named Best Film by the National Board of Review in 1972.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, scotland,
based on play or musical, rise to power, 11th century.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.